A Guide to the Robert C. Siegfried Genealogical Research Files, 1938-1996
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Robert C. Siegfried Genealogical Research Files, 1938-1996
The Library of Virginia
44879
1.8 cubic feet (4 boxes)
Siegfried, Robert C., 1919-2002
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert Siegfried II, Midlothian, Virginia, 17 March 2010 and 1 February 2011.
Biographical Information
Robert C. Siegfried (1919-2002) was the great-grandson of William Smith (1812-1879) and Harriet Winifred Pace Smith. William Smith operated a lime burning plant on the turning basin of the James River and Kanawha Canal until 1862, when he purchased Barnfield, in Henrico County, and became a farmer. After Smith's death, his son William Wirt Smith and wife Martha Ella Horne Smith lived on the portion of the original Barnfield property inherited by W. W. Smith. They built a house on the land and raised two daughters there. After W. W. Smith's death, daughter Mary (May) Coleman Smith Siegfried and husband Lindsay Bledsoe Siegfried (d. 1949) moved to the Barnfield house, raising a family of five children, including Robert C. Siegfried. The property was sold to Thalhimer's Department Store in the early 1950's.
Scope and Content
Genealogical research files compiled by Robert C. Siegfried (1919-2002), including materials gathered on the following families: Blaettermann (Blattermann), Bledsoe (Bletsho, Bletsoe, and Bletchers), Copenhaver, Farris, Getty, Horne, Lindsay, Miller, Pace, Siegfried, Smith, Snead, and Walker. The types of materials collected include transcripts of primary documents such as wills, land grants, and census records; family trees; family researcher newsletters; photographs; and genealogical notes reports written by Siegfried and other researchers. Siegfried's own memoirs of his youth, entitled "Barnfield: A 'Great Depression' Home in Henrico County, Virginia, 1919-1940," offer multiple vignettes and details of daily life at that time in the vicinity of Staples Mill Road and Broad Street (Road) in Henrico County.
Arrangement
Original order has been maintained. Where applicable, original folder and volume titles have been retained.
Contents List
- Robert C. Siegfried genealogical research files, 1938-1996., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 1-4)
  - Barnfield: A "Great Depression" Home in Henrico County, Virginia, 1919-1940, Recollections by R. C. Siegfried, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Barnfield" 1919-1940: A "Great Depression" Home in Henrico County, Virginia, Personal recollections of Robert Coleman Siegfried, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Blaettermann (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bledsoe (binder) (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Bledsoe Family Quarterly, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6-13)
  - Bledsoe Charts (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Bledsoe Notes (Box 2, Folder 5-9)
  - Bledsoe, Bletsho, Bletsoe, Bletchers (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Notes Gathered on the Family of Bledsoe from the Records of the States of Virginia, Kentucky, Georgia and Tennessee (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Copenhaver (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Some Descendants of Ralph R. Horne of King William County, Virginia (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Lindsays of the Mount: A Correction, by Bob Siegfried (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miller and Farris families (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pace, William (Texas research) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Siegfried Family of 'Gale Hill,' Fluvanna Co., Va., R. C. Siegfried, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Henry David Siegfried: A Short Outline of Some of the Antecedents and Descendants of Henry David Siegfried, the Immigrant to Virginia in c. 183[?], compiled by Robert Coleman Siegfried (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Descendants of Henry David Siegfried, Immigrant, and Anna Christiana Blaettermann, compiled by R. C. Siegfried, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Final Accounting of the Sale of Items in the Estate of Virginia Champion Siegfried, Nee Bledsoe, Wife of John Henry Carl August Siegfried, Gale Hill, Fluvanna Co., Va. in the Year 1902 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Some Notes Gathered on the Family of George R. Smith, Lower Hanover County, Virginia, compiled by R. C. Siegfried, 1985. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Snead-Siegfried-Getty photographs (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
  - An Account of Some of the Antecedents and Descendants of James Alexander Walker, Physician, Bedford County, Virginia, compiled by R. C. "Bob" Siegfried. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Includes original Bible record for the family of James A. Walker (1868-1948) and Willie Paulina Keesear Walker (1875-1949) of Botetourt County. A copy of this record is filed as LVA Accession 34817.